# **Maxim Danilov**

**J** +43(681)207-44-776

**∠** maxim@wpshop.at

in linkedin.com/in/danilovmy

github.com/danilovmy

Languages: conversational English and German, basic Italian, native Russian

## SUMMARY

I am a senior developer and software architect for the past 27 years. I have led teams, launched startups, spoken at technology conferences, write and reviewed tons of code, and contributed to open-source.

Looking positions: Senior Python Developer, Team Lead.

**Desired tasks and future goals:** Grow into a Principal Software Engineer, leading software development, working with development teams, mentoring teams, speak on conferences, learn Rust.

### **EDUCATION**

Moscow Power Engineering Institute - Master's degree in Electronics and Microelectronics. Erickson Coaching International - Mental Coach in Management.

## SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

- Software development, 27 years.
- Tech Mentoring and Code Coaching, 27 years of work with students, mentees, employee.
- Work with SQL and No-SQL Databases, 25 years.
- Pyton/Django 9 years, VueJs/NuxtJs 5 years.
- Team Leadership 7 years of experience.

Additional skills: DRF, Django-Admin, GeoDjango, FastAPI, Pydantic, Deno.Fresh, ReportLab, JavaScript, AWS, public speaking to large audiences, adapted for startup environment.

## Working experience

#### Senior Developer Consultant, 2023-2024, 0.5 years

Solving architectural issues in diverse projects. Python 3, Asyncio, FastAPI, LiteStar, Django, AWS.

#### Owner, CTO, Tech Lead, Software Architect in wP soft GmbH 2020-2023, 3 years

Develop python-based web solutions and micro-services per demand. Tech stack: Python 3, Django, DRF, FastAPI, Vue.Js/Nuxt.Js, PostgreSQL, MySQL, ReportLab, nginx...

- Created from scratch and served as the architect an e-commerce and time accounting platform and established a high-load PDF generation service as SaaS.
- Mantainer of open-source Python/Django translation library: Django-TOF2.
- Build a project team: 3 developers, designer and intern and provided programming mentorship.

Co-owner, Senior Software Developer, Software Architect in winePad.at 2015-2020, 6 years Built a biggest tech database about Alcohol in Europe. Tech stack: Python 2.7, Django, ReportLab, BeautifulSoup4, Elasticsearch, with SQL/NoSQL DB, javascript, jQuery, Lighttpd, DRF...

- Developed winePad.at from scratch to a successful mature project with over 800k lines of code. Created road-map for project and maintain architecture.
- Author of services: PDF generator, import-export system, full-text/image search solution.
- Organized data exchange services for systems: WooCommerce, Xenia, Supra, Bollichine.

Co-owner, CEO in Alpinbus GmbH, 2014-2016, 2 years. Low-code platforms, Zapier, AWS. Co-owner, CTO in linguaXtrem GmbH, 2010-2013, 4 years. PHP, JavaScript, Trados, MemoQ.

CEO in Extra-service, 2006-2009, 3 years. PHP, JavaScript.

Technician in Siemens-Infineon Laboratory, 1997-2006, 9 years. Assembly, Fortran, C, Pascal. Software Developer in AF Trans International, 1999-2004, 5 years. VB, VBA, .NET, ODBC.